<!--

  intro.xml          ramega package documentation                 Zsolt Adam Balogh
																  Vasyl Laver

  Copyright (C) 2020  Zsolt Adam Balogh, Vasyl Laver, Department of Mathematical Sciences,
  UAEU, Al Ain, United Arab Emirates
  This file is free software, see license information at the end.

  This chapter gives a short introduction and explains the philosophy
  behind the package.

-->

<Chapter Label="intro">
<Heading>Introduction</Heading>


<Package>RAMEGA</Package> stands for ``RAndom MEthods in Group ALgebras".
This package is dedicated to realization of some standard functions for group rings by the means of the random methods. This approach allows to compute the needed function
in a reasonable time and with minimal memory use even for the large group rings <Cite Key="Bovdi_Rosa_I"/>.<P/>

The main purpose of <Package>RAMEGA</Package> is to deal with the group of units of group algebras, in particular,
modular group algebras. In modular case the order of group of units is an exponential function
of the order of basic group. Therefore the size of group of units can be very large even for smaller
basic groups. This package contains random functions corresponding to the properties of
group of units of group algebras. Most functions also can be found in <Package>LAGUNA</Package> <Cite Key="LAGUNA3.9.0"/>, but due to
random methods, their computation time are significantly reduced in <Package>RAMEGA</Package>.<P/>

<Package>RAMEGA</Package> also contains functions related to Lie properties of group algebras and there are some functions
that work for any group structure not only for group algebras.<P/>

<Section Label="overview">
<Heading>Overview over this manual</Heading>
Chapter <Ref Chap="random"/> describes the functions for group algebras which were obtained using the random methods. There are three subchapters in it.
The first one, <Ref Chap="random_basic"/>, describes some basic operations for group algebras, which don't involve randomness. Chapter <Ref Chap="random_methods_elements"/>
describes the methods, which return the elements with some desired property by a random way. Chapter <Ref Chap="random_methods_general"/> describes some general methods for
group algebras. All the methods in this section also return the result by a random way.  
</Section>

<Section Label="instal">
<Heading>Installation</Heading>
To get the newest version of this &GAP; 4 package download the
archive file <F>ramega-x.x.tar.gz</F> and unpack it in a directory called <Q><F>pkg</F></Q>, preferably (but not
necessarily) in the <Q><F>pkg</F></Q> subdirectory of your &GAP; 4
installation. It creates a subdirectory called <Q><F>RAMEGA</F></Q>.<P/>

As <Package>RAMEGA</Package> has no additional C libraries, there is no need in any additional installation steps.<P/>

</Section>


<Section Label="feedback">
<Heading>Feedback</Heading>

For bug reports, feature requests and suggestions, please use the github issue tracker at <URL>https://github.com/vlaver/RAMEGA/issues</URL>.
</Section>





<!-- ############################################################ -->

</Chapter>

<!--
  This program is free software; you can redistribute it and/or modify
  it under the terms of the GNU General Public License as published by
  the Free Software Foundation; version 2 of the License.

  This program is distributed in the hope that it will be useful,
  but WITHOUT ANY WARRANTY; without even the implied warranty of
  MERCHANTABILITY or FITNESS FOR A PARTICULAR PURPOSE.  See the
  GNU General Public License for more details.

  You should have received a copy of the GNU General Public License
  along with this program; if not, write to the Free Software
  Foundation, Inc., 59 Temple Place, Suite 330, Boston, MA  02111-1307  USA
-->
